Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Course Bulletins MC.286
New York University Archives
- School of Professional Studies (RG 32), 1903-ongoing
  - School of Professional Studies Degree Directory, August 2019-ongoing
    Online course directory for the NYU School of Professional Studies. The website is broken down by area of study, degree program, and department. Each degree listed can include an overview of the degree, program structure, program requirements, admission criteria, program flexibility, and financial aid. The core requirements and concentration sections links to full course descriptions for classes in each degree.
  - School of Professional Studies Graduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The SPS bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their masters programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
  - School of Professional Studies Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The SPS bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their undergraduate programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
- School of Professional Studies - American Language Institute for International Students (RG 32.1), 1964-1976
  - Bulletins, 1964-1965, 1967-1971, 1974-1976 (Box 148)
- School of Professional Studies - Real Estate Institute (RG 32.3), 1970-1993
  - Bulletins, 1970-1971, 1974-1988 (Box 149)
  - Bulletins, 1988-1997, 2000-2001 (Box 150)
  - Bulletins, 1992-1993 (Box 137)
- School of Professional Studies - Paul McGhee Division (RG 32.12), 1985-2012
  - Bulletins, 1985-1992 (Box 151)
  - Bulletins, 1992-2001 (Box 152)
  - Bulletins, 2000-2012 (Box 153)
- School of Professional Studies - General Studies Program (RG 32.13), 1979-1992
  - Bulletins, 1979-1983, 1991-1992 (Box 154)
- Paterson Collegiate Center (RG 32.40), 1926-1932
  - Bulletins, 1926-1932 (Box 184)
- Newark Institute of Arts and Sciences (RG 32.41), 1915-1916
  - Announcements, 1915-1916 (Box 184)
- Westchester County Centers (RG 32.42), 1928-1931
  - Bulletins, 1928-1931 (Box 184)
- Hempstead Center (RG 32.43), 1930-1931
  - Bulletins, 1930-1931 (Box 184)
- Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service (RG 33), 1938-2011, April 2014-ongoing
  The Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service offers curricula covering domestic and international issues including nonprofit management, financial management, public policy analysis, urban public policy studies, urban planning, and health policy and management. Masters and doctoral degree programs are offered on both full-time and part-time bases. The Advanced Professional Certificate Programs and the Master of Science in Management Program offer career development opportunities for experienced professionals.
  - Bulletins, 1938-1944, 1947-1963 (Box 155)
  - Bulletins, 1963-1982 (Box 156)
  - Bulletins, 1982-1995 (Box 157)
  - Bulletins, 1996-2011 (Box 158)
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, April 2014-October 2016
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Hunger and Food Security in a Global Perspective, May 2014-July 2017
    Course description and syllabi for the Hunger and Food Security in a Global Perspective course in Accra, Ghana at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Urbanization and Sustainable Development in a Transitional Economy: Experiencing China, May 2014-March 2021
    Course description and syllabi for the Urbanization and Sustainable Development in a Transitional Economy: Experiencing China course in Shanghai, China at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Bulletin, October 2016-November 2017
    PDF of the Graduate School of Public Service bulletin for 2015-2017.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, May 2017-June 2021
    Website containing course information for Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service. It includes course highlights, courses across NYU that can be taken as pre-approved electives, courses abroad, capstone information, independent study, non-Wagner student enrollment in Wagner courses, program requirement checklists, course evaluations, skills workshops, and undergraduate and graduate course schedules by semester. Each semester since Fall 2017 the page featured course highlights, linking to descriptions of new courses, returning courses not taught the previous year, courses that require application, courses with intensive format, saturday courses, courses with new titles, and courses with new instructors.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Nonprofit Governance, July 2017-June 2019
    Course description and syllabi for the Nonprofit Governance course at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Transformative Participation for Democratic Practice, July 2017-August 2018
    Course description and syllabi for the Transformative Participation for Democratic Practice course at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, August 2018-ongoing
    Listing of all course descriptions for NYU Wagner.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Degree Programs, August 2018-ongoing
    Information on the following graduate degree programs at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service: Master of Public Administration-Public & Nonprofit Management & Policy; Master of Public Administration-Health Policy & Management; Master of Urban Planning; Master of Science in Public Policy; Executive Master of Public Administration; PhD in Public Administration; Online Master of Health Administration; and global Executive MPA: Joint degree with UCL. Specific degree program pages focus on specializations, tracks, coursework, degree requirements and faculty.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, March 2019-March 2021
    Listing of all course descriptions for Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Bulletin, October 2019-ongoing
    Bulletin for the Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service. Includes general admission requirements; description and requirements of academic programs for the Master of Public Administration, Health Policy and Management, Master of Urban Planning, Online Master of Health Administration, Master of Science in Public Policy, PhD in Public Administration, dual-degree programs, and undergraduate offerings. Also includes course listings, library and program-related facilities, academic calendar, cost of attendance, and financial assistance.
  - Master of Science in Health Law and Strategy Curriculum, February 2022-February 2023
    Semester by semester course descriptions for the Master of Science in Health Law and Strategy, a joint program of NYU Law and NYU Wagner.
  - Master of Science in Health Law and Strategy Curriculum, February 2023-ongoing
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Graduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Wagner bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their masters, certificate, and PhD programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each program.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Wagner bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their undergraduate partnerships with other NYU schools. It also includes the program requirements for each minor.
- Silver School of Social Work (RG 34), 1960-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1960-1986 (Box 159)
  - Bulletins, 1986-2010 (Box 160)
  - Bulletin (PDF), 2013-2014; cuid17995
  - Silver School of Social Work Bulletin, April 2014-May 2015
    PDF of the Silver School bulletin for 2013-2014.
  - Silver School of Social Work PhD Curriculum, September 2016-March 2020
    Webpage detailing the program requirements and curriculum content for the PhD in Social Work at the Silver School.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bachelor of Science Course Descriptions, September 2016-March 2020
    Course descriptions of required and elective courses for the Bachelor of Science at the Silver School of Social Work.
  - Silver School of Social Work Master of Social Work Course Descriptions, September 2016-March 2020
    Website featuring course descriptions for the Master of Social Work at the Silver School. From 2016-2017, the course descriptions are organized by first year (Professional Foundation) courses, second year (Advanced Concentration in Clinical Practice), and electives. In 2018, the name of the requirements of the Master's changed and are organized by first year (Generalist Practice), Second Year (Specialized Practice), three-credit electives, and one credit electives.
  - Silver School of Social Work Student Manuals and Community Standards, September 2016-May 2017
    PDFs of the BS Student Manual, MSW Student Manual, PhD Student Manual, DSW Student Manual, Silver School Academic Bulletin, and the Silver School of Social Work Credit Hour Policy.
  - Silver School of Social Work Academics, September 2016-May 2017
    Landing page for the Silver School academics program containing program student manuals for the Bachelor of Science, Master of Social Work, PhD, Doctorate in Clinical Social Work programs, as well as the credit hour policy and academic bulletin for 2015-2017
  - Silver School of Social Work Study Abroad, October 2016-March 2020
    Course listings for Silver School's study abroad courses. Contains information for MSW and semester programs at study abroad sites as well as single course offerings for 2017-2020.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bulletin, August 2018-March 2020
    PDF of the Silver School bulletin for 2017-2019.
  - Silver School of Social Work Master of Social Work, June 2020-ongoing
    Overview of the Master of Social Work at the Silver School, covering degree pathways, curriculum, course descriptions, non-matriculated and online options, study abroad options, and application information. The degree pathways include course sequences for part-time and full-time options for the Master's program, as well as dual degree options. The curriculum consists of a Generalist Practice level followed by a Specialized Practice level and course descriptions in these practices.
  - Silver School of Social Work Global Opportunities, June 2020-ongoing
    Overview of Social Work classes offered at NYU study abroad locations, including course descriptions, with a specific focus on the Shanghai-New York MSW program.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bachelor of Science, June 2020-ongoing
    Overview of the Bachelor of Science at the Silver School, covering curriculum, student experience, admissions, and an FAQ. The curriculum pages cover the course of study required for the major, dual major and minors, and study abroad.
  - Silver School of Social Work Doctorate in Clinical Social Work, June 2020-ongoing
    Overview of the Doctorate in Clinical Social Work at the Silver School, covering curriculum, course sequence, faculty, course descriptions, student and alumni accomplishments, and application information.
  - Silver School of Social Work Doctor of Philosophy, June 2020-ongoing
    Overview of the Doctor of Philosophy at the Silver School, covering curriculum, faculty, research, teaching experience, their lecture series, and student success stories. The website also covers the program requirements, including course descriptions of the social work core classes, advanced methodological/statistical courses, and substantive area of expertise courses, as well information on career preparation, the research practicum, qualifying exam, and dissertation.
  - Silver School of Social Work NYU Silver Experience, February-March 2022
    PDF of the viewbook for the Silver School of Social Work for the Masters of Social Work degree.
  - Silver School of Social Work Graduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Silver bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their DSW, MSW, and PhD programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
  - Silver School of Social Work Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Silver bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their undergraduate majors and minors. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
- Tisch School of the Arts (RG 35), 1986-ongoing
  The Tisch School of the Arts offers the B.A., B.F.A., M.F.A., M.P.S., M.A. (moving image archiving and preservation), and, through the Graduate School of Arts and Science, the M.A. (performance studies or cinema studies) and Ph.D degrees. Departments and programs offering professional training are acting, dance, design, drama, performance studies, film and television, cinema studies, photography and imaging, dramatic writing, musical theatre writing, recorded music, and interactive telecommunications.
  - Bulletins, 1966-1984 (Box 161)
  - Bulletins, 1983-1992 (Box 162)
  - Bulletins, 1991-2003 (Box 163)
  - Bulletins, 2003-2013 (Box 164)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2009-2011, 2013-2015
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin, April 2014-May 2016
  - Tisch School of the Arts: A Troubleshooter's Guide to Tisch and New York University (for Parents!), May-September 2016
    PDF of a guide for parents of Tisch students on housing, health, financial aid, academic issues, and social adjustment.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May-October 2016
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook for 2015-2016.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Academic Integrity Policy, May-October 2016
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts Academic Integrity Policy.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin 2015-2017, May 2016-April 2017
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts bulletin for 2015-2017.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Student Affairs, May 2016-March 2019
    Website featuring information for students in Tisch. Includes information on academic services, student life, career development, financial aid, international students, parents, new student orientation, graduation, forms, tuition, housing, and staff.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May 2016-ongoing
    Policies and procedures handbook for the Tisch School of the Arts, which includes information about health and immunizations, registration and enrollment, discipline, harassment, grievance procedures, academic policies and procedures, and other student services.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May 2016-ongoing
    PDFs for the Policies and Procedures Handbook, starting in 2015. The handbook covers matters such as academic standards, grading policies, registration regulations, and degree requirements.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin, May 2016-ongoing
    Landing page linking to a PDF of the Tisch Bulletin. Links to PDFs of bulletins from 2015-2017, 2017-2019, and 2019-2021.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin 2017-2019, November 2017-October 2019
    Tisch School of the Arts course Bulletin for 2017-2019, which includes a faculty directory, academic calendar, administrative information about Tisch, descriptions of each department in the Institute of Performing Arts and the Maurice Kanbar Institute of Film and Television, and course listings by degree program.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook 2019-2020, October 2019
  - Tisch School of the Arts Graduate Bulletin, February 2024-ongoing
    The Tisch bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their masters programs, as well as interdisciplinary partnerships with other NYU schools. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Tisch bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their undergraduate majors and minors. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each degree.
- Gallatin School of Individualized Study (RG 36), 1981-2012, April 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1981-1998 (Box 165)
  - Bulletins, 1998-2005 (Box 166)
  - Bulletins, 2006-2010 (Box 167)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2009-2012; cuid17996
  - Gallatin School of Individual Study Bulletin, April 2014-June 2020
    This page houses the Bulletin for New York University's Gallatin School of Individualized Study, with information about the structure and goals of individualized study programs, degree requirements, the IAPC essay, and the colloquium requirement for undergraduate students, as well as course offerings, study abroad opportunities, admissions, and financial aid resources. The page also details core courses and independent study components for individualized Master of Arts programs through Gallatin, and lists student resources and faculty profiles.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Course Directory, October 2016-October 2023
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Graduate Academics, October 2016-ongoing
    Website detailing the components of graduate education at Gallatin. The website includes information degree requirements, the curriculum for enrollees before and after summer 2013, the master's thesis, graduate student community, and financial aid. The website details the core courses, elective courses, independent study, tutorials, internships, private lessons, advising, courses outside of NYU, and other NYU courses.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Undergraduate Academics, October 2016-ongoing
    Website detailing the components of undergraduate education at Gallatin. The website includes the structure of the four-year program, degree requirements, study in other schools at NYU, global study, civic engagements, other learning opportunities, and student-directed learning. The website contains course descriptions for the first-year program, interdisciplinary seminars, advanced writing, and arts workshops. It also includes degree requirements, plan for the concentration, and the practicum.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Course Catalog, July 2021-ongoing
  - Gallatin Fall 2022 Course Directory, October 2022
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin for Fall 2022. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
  - Gallatin Summer 2023 Course Directory, June 2023
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin for Summer 2023. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
  - Gallatin Fall 2023 Course Directory, October 2023
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin for Fall 2023. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Graduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Gallatin bulletin provides an overview of the policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of Gallatin's masters program.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Gallatin bulletin provides an overview of the policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of Gallatin's undergraduate program.
  - Gallatin Spring 2024 Course Directory, February 2024
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin for Spring 2024. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
- Prison Education Program (RG 36.4), October 2021-ongoing
  - Prison Education Program Faculty and Courses, October 2021-ongoing
    Website containing a faculty list and an overview of the curriculum and example courses in the Associate's Degree Program in Liberal Studies at Wallkill Correctional Facility.
- Deutsches Haus (RG 37.3), 1977-1995
  - German language courses, 1977, 1981-1982, 1987-1992, 1995 (Box 168)
- Center for International Studies (RG 37.5), 1965-1971
  - Bulletins, 1965-1971 (Box 169)
- Institute for Hebrew and Judaic Studies (RG 37.8), 1963-1972
  - Bulletins, 1963-1972 (Box 170)
- Center for Near Eastern Studies (RG 37.14), 1987-1990
  - Bulletins, 1987-1990 (Box 170)
- Nassau College-Hofstra Memorial (RG 37.32), 1934-1939
  - Bulletins, 1934-1939 (Box 171)
- Center for Urban Science and Progress (RG 37.52), July 2017-ongoing
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Course Catalogue, July-November 2017
    Course descriptions for graduate courses at the Center for Urban Science and Progress (CUSP), including non-credit required courses, required core courses, and CUSP electives.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science Curriculum, August 2018-October 2021
    Overview of the master of science curriculum at CUSP. The webpage includes preparatory resources, core course descriptions, electives descriptions, capstone projects, and student immersions.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics, March 2019-October 2023
    Website detailing the Master of Science program at the Center for Urban Science and Progress. Includes an overview of the program, curriculum, admissions requirements, tuition and financial aid, application guide, and admissions FAQ.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science Curriculum, June 2019-ongoing
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Online Advanced Certificate, October 2022-October 2023
    This website contains course descriptions for the Advanced Certificate in Applied Urban Science and Informatics.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress BS in Sustainable Urban Environments & MS in Applied Urban Science and Progress, October-November 2022
    Website detailing the five year combined NYU Tandon School of Engineering's Bachelor of Science in Sustainable Urban Environments and NYU CUSP's Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics. Website includes the curriculum and application requirements.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Course Catalog, November 2022-ongoing
    Google document of required core classes and electives for the Master's program at the Center for Urban Science and Progress.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Doctoral Track, February-October 2023